let quiz = [
    {
        question: 'Binary fission is found in',
        options: [
            'Amoeba ',
            'Paramecium',
            'Planaria ',
            'All of these',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Basal half of an onion bulb is removed and upper half is sown in the ground. New plant will',
        options: [
            'emerge normally ',
            'not emerge',
            'be without leaves ',
            'be without flowers',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'A small portion of cane-sugar stem between the two successive nodes is cut off and sown in the soil normally. New plants will',
        options: [
            'be formed normally ',
            'not be formed',
            'be without juice ',
            'without nodes',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'What is necessary for successful grafting to occur ?',
        options: [
            'Each section must be able to form roots.',
            'The grafted section must be able to form seeds.',
            'Fusion of the two vascular tissues must occur.',
            'Fusion of the two cambial tissues must occur.',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'In all the methods of asexual reproduction',
        options: [
            'offsprings produced are genetically identical to the parents.',
            'offsprings produced are genetically different from the parents.',
            'offsprings produced may or may not be identical to the parents.',
            'None of these',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'Banana fruits are seedless, because',
        options: [
            'auxins are sprayed for rapid development of fruit.',
            'vegetative propagation of plant.',
            'they are triploid plants.',
            'fruits are artificially ripened.',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Soil around stem of potato plant is constantly removed from very young stage so that only roots remain in the soil. Potato tubers in plant will',
        options: [
            'be larger ',
            'be smaller',
            'be formed normally ',
            'not be formed',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'A potato tuber is sown in a pot and pot is placed in the freezer of refrigerator. New plants will',
        options: [
            'emerge normally ',
            'not emerge',
            'be without leaves ',
            'be without flowers',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Asexual reproduction takes place in',
        options: [
            'higher animals ',
            'lower animals',
            'plants ',
            'All of these',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'As a result of binary fission number of individuals produced by one fission is',
        options: ['two ', 'three', 'four ', 'five'],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which of the following definitions about oviparity is false ?',
        options: [
            'Only birds and reptiles are oviparous.',
            'The large amount of yolk provides the nutrients for the developing embryo.',
            'The shell protects the egg from dehydration.',
            'Both oxygen and carbon dioxide can diffuse through the shell.',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Seeds are regarded to be the product of sexual reproduction because they',
        options: [
            'Can be stored for a long period.',
            'Give rise to new plants.',
            'Are the result of fusion of male gamete with the female gamete.',
            'None of these',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which of the following statements about animals that utilize external fertilization is false?',
        options: [
            'They are divided equally between terrestrial and aquatic species.',
            'Many produce large numbers of gametes to ensure successful reproduction.',
            'The behaviours associated with mating are often highly synchronized.',
            'The probability of any one egg being fertilized and developing into an adult can be low.',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Consider the following statements and choose the correct option.',
        statement: [
            '(I) The genetic constitution of a plant is unaffected in vegetative propagation.',
            '(II) Rhizome in ginger serves as an organ of vegetative reproduction.',
            '(III) Totipotency of cells enables us to micropropagate plants.',
        ],
        options: [
            'Statements (I) and (II) alone are true',
            'Statements (II) and (III) alone are true',
            'Statement (II) alone is true',
            'All the three statements (I), (II) and (III) are true',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which of the following animals qualifies as a sexually reproducing, oviparous species ?',
        options: ['Human ', 'Chicken', 'Kangaroo ', 'Sea star'],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'During spermatogenesis a single male germ cell produces _____ sperm cell(s).',
        options: ['1 ', '2', '3 ', '4'],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'Find the correct combination.',
        options: [
            'Zoospore in sponge ',
            'Gemmules in Penicillium',
            'Conidia in algae ',
            'Buds in Hydra',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'The chromosome number is haploid in',
        options: ['zygote ', 'gamete', 'embryo ', 'seed'],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Plants identical to mother plants can be obtained from',
        options: [
            'seeds ',
            'stem cutting',
            'Both and ',
            'None of these',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'A clone is a group of individuals obtained through',
        options: [
            'self-pollination',
            'hybridization',
            'vegetative propagation',
            'cross-pollination',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Ploidy of ovary, anther, egg, pollen, male gamete and zygote are respectively-',
        options: [
            '2n, 2n, n, 2n, n, 2n ',
            '2n, 2n, n, n, n, 2n',
            '2n, n, n, n, n, n ',
            '2n, 2n, n, 2n, 2n, 2n',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Fleshy buds produced in the axil of leaves, which grow to form new plants when shed and fall on ground, are called',
        options: ['Bulbs ', 'Bulbils', 'Tubers ', 'Offsets'],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Offsprings of oviparous animals are at greater risk as compared to offsprings of viviparous animals because-',
        options: [
            'Proper embryonic care and protection is lesser',
            'Embryo is not developed',
            'Progenies are with more variation',
            'Progenies are larger',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'Syngamy means',
        options: [
            'fusion of similar spores.',
            'fusion of gametes.',
            'fusion of dissimilar spores.',
            'fusion of cytoplasm.',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'A plant differs from an animal mainly in:',
        options: [
            'protoplasm ',
            'vital activities',
            'nutrition ',
            'reproduction',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
];
